Edgar Said Hernández Sánchez

Sumary

I'm a fugitive of three Math University Faculties now making a life as a Professional Software Developer, Sr. Procrastinator and Jr. Father.

I have 7+ years of experience developing mostly web applications using C# and javascript.

I love to solve problems and I like to participate in all kind of programming contests.

Education

Universidad Abierta y a Distancia de México (UNADM)

01/2015 - Current Online

B.S. Mathematics. (Lic. en Matemáticas)

Facultad de Matemáticas de la Universidad de Guanajuato. (CIMAT)

08/2002 - 07/2007 Guanajuato, Mexico

B.S. Computer science. (Lic. En Computación)

Truncated in last semester with 90% of completion.

Experience

Software Developer (Computer Information Systems Assistant)

<u>United Nations Office on Drugs and Crime/Conference Management Service/Applications</u>

<u>Development Team</u>

01/2013 - current

- Developed a tool in F# to deploy several report projects to several SQL Server Reporting Services servers reducing the deployment time and allowing CI and automatic deployment with Octopus Deploy.
- Participated in the development of a new AngularJS application (http://myconference.unov.org) to show the integrated information of UN's Conferences gathered automatically from the internal management systems allowing UN delegates to access the information, documents and digital recordings on their mobile devices before and after the conference.
- Maintenance and Development of new features for two ASP .Net MVC 3 applications used to manage the services required for the smooth functioning of UN conferences all over the globe.
- Currently I am part of a team developing a "Computer Aided Translation" tool.

Software Development Engineer

Knowtion

08/2012 - 12/2012

- Development of a web application to administrate communication between several RabbitMQ instances.
- Participated in the maintenance and development of new functionalities for a C#/WPF application.

Sr. Software Development Engineer

Grupo Advantage

03/2011 - 08/2012

- Designed and developed a tool to load historical data from production log files and send them in several concurrent threads to an Invoice Emission Service allowing the team to implement regression and stress test for this service.
- Designed and developed a Thin Client for an Invoice Validation Service helping Grupo Advantage's clients to validate thousands of invoices in minutes instead of days.
- Designed and developed a component to generate and validate API keys used to connect to the public API of Grupo Advantage.
- Participated on the development of the front end and backend of a web application used to validate XML invoices.

Lead Developer / Cofounder

Corporación Augures

11/2010 - 02/2012

- Responsible for the technical decisions concerning the development tools, databases, and deployment environments for the company applications.
- Designed and developed a Client-Server C#/WPF/WCF application to calculate the assignment of assets in portfolios using the Mean-Variance Model of Harry Markowitz in a dynamic way.

Technical Leader / Technical Specialist (Pre-sales)

IDS Comercial - Client: IBM Mexico

11/2009 - 02/2011

- Led a team of 5 developers and introduced Code Reviews and Test Driven Development methodologies improving the code quality in general.
- Led a project to replace a Business Process Manager (BPM) used in an application, from a vendor solution to a custom BPM, unsuccessfully trying to improve the overall performance.
- Participated in the creation of two successful sales projects analysing and estimating the requirements.

Analyst Programmer

Digipro S.A.

03/2008 - 11/2009

• Designed and developed the document visualisation web control for the Application Portal taking

in consideration all the security restrictions imposed by the banks.

• Developed a tool to configure new instances of the main application reducing the configuration time of a project from 4 days to 4 hours.

Software Developer

CIMAT Software Development Factory

09/2006 - 02/2008

- Developed an image-based measurement plugin that could be used on static images and videos using Borland C++ Builder 6 and DirectShow.
- Participated in the design of a module for hand writing recognition.

Technical Skills

- .Net C#, ASP .Net MVC, WPF, WCF
- JavaScript jQuery, AngularJs, Vanilla JavaScript
- SQL MS SQL Server 2005-2012
- Additional known (basic level) programming languages: Ruby, Objective-C, Python, F#, Swift

Achievements

- Finalist in Google Code Jam Latinamerica 2007
- First and second place in several Component Development Contests in TopCoder. Profile

Projects

+###Trainer/Leader +Guanjuato State Informatics Olympiad (OIEG) +November 2004 - December 2007 +The OIEG is an independent non-profit organisation whose main activity is the organisation of the Informatics Olympiad at the State level in Guanajuato Mexico. Hosted under funding from the Universidad de Guanajuato and the Centre for Mathematical Research (CIMAT) and composed of about 10 voluntary trainers and advisors. Each year, the OIEG organises a programming contest over many high schools in the state to select a team of the best students that will represent the State in the National competition. Guanajuato's team has obtained the overall first place nationally 9 of the last 10 years, including twice while I was a trainer and advisor.

Certifications

- MCTS Microsoft .NET Framework 3.5, ASP.NET Application Development in C#
- MCTS: Web Applications Development with Microsoft .NET Framework 4

Transcript

Transcript ID (1001890)

Access Code (edgarshs)

Links

- Github Profile
- Personal Blog
- Stack Overflow Profile
- <u>TopCoder Profile</u>
- <u>Linkedin</u>
- <u>Twitter</u>